

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING . MACHINE LEARNING . DATA PROCESSING

Oberschlossfeld 33. Willisau, 6130. Switzerland

🛮 (+41) 79-960-8333 | 🗷 andrew.presland@gmail.com | 🐔 www.presland.io | 🖸 apresland | 🛅 apresland

Objective.

I seek a role in machine perception, computer vision and autonomous systems. I bring professional experience as a machine learning and software engineer which is combined with a background in scientific computing and data analytics for particle physics (CERN Reseach Fellow). Focus has been achieved by recent certifications and portfolio projects in deep learning, robotics and computer vision.

Experience_

Data Scientist Luzern, Switzerland

AxonVIBE AG.

2018 - 2021

- Built models that used mobile sensor data (GNSS/IMU) to detect behavioural patterns in users mobility using Neural Networks, Gradient Boosting, Spatio-Temporal clustering and Markov Models.
- Built serverless data-monitoring, anomaly detection, and feature extraction pipelines in Python using AWS Lambda, Batch and S3
- Productionized Significant Location Detection in Java as a Spring Boot Batch service including ETL and JDBC data connections as a Spring Boot RESTful service and visualization with Javascript frontend dashboard.

Senior Software Engineer Luzern, Switzerland

BBV SOFTWARE SERVICES AG.

2010 - 2018

- Delivered testable embedded software for RTOS and Embedded Linux using Agile, and Extreme Programming.
- Developed communication (TCP/IP) and security (SSL/TLS) modules, and Hardware Abstraction Layers for IoT devices and fieldbus based distributed motion control solutions for industrial robots.
- Quality Assurance Engineering with executable behaviour specification in Cucumber, artifact management with JFrog and test with Appium and CI with Jenkins.

Project Leader (Software)

Luzern, Switzerland

HAGENBUCH HYDRAULIC SYSTEMS AG.

2006 - 2010

- Development of real-time motion control systems for 6DOF parallel kinematic manipulators (Stewart Platforms) and Vibration Analysis rigs using distributed control systems connected by fieldbus and real-time signal processing for spectral analysis and HMI development using .Net.
- Level-2 technical support.

Research Fellow (Applied Physics)

Geneva, Switzerland

EUROPEAN ORGANIZATION FOR NUCLEAR RESEARCH (CERN)

2003 - 2006

- Computational Physics developer creating simulations for Accelerator Driven Systems (ADS) on the CERN high performance computing cluster.
- Monte-Carlo simulation of multi-particle transport for thermal energy deposition and radiation damage in the LHC control electronics under beam accident scenarios. The studies ultimately ensured the correct and sage operation of the LHC.

Post Doctoral Research Associate (High Energy Physics)

Geneva, Switzerland

H. H. WILLS PHYSICS LABORATORY, UNIVERSITY OF BRISTOL

2001 - 2003

- Member of the LHCb collaboration searching for the source of matter-antimatter asymmetry in the universe by studying sub-atomic particles containing b-quarks.
- Contributed to the physics Object Data Model, developed reconstruction code for the Event Data Processing Framework (Gaudi) and performed Monte-Carlo simulation and Scientific Data Analysis using ROOT Data Analysis Framework.

Doctoral Researcher (High Energy Physics)

Bristol, UK 1998 - 2001

H. H. WILLS PHYSICS LABORATORY, UNIVERSITY OF BRISTOL

- Member of the CMS collaboration, a general purpose detector at the LHC primarily focussed on the search for the Higgs Boson.
- · Prototyping of the PbWO4 scintillating crystal calorimeters and photon detector readout for detecting electromagnetic particels.
- Reconstruction of particle energy using clustering algorithms to process signals from photon sensor readout.

Skills

Code Python, C++, Cuda, JAVA, Scala, MATLAB, SQL

Numerical Pobability, Statistics, Linear Algebra, Calculus, Scientific Data Analysis

Frameworks Tensorflow, Keras, TensorRT, OpenCV, Scikit-learn, numpy, pandas, scipy, Jupyter

ML / Al CNN, RNN, LSTM, GAN, Object Detection, Random Forest, Gradient Boosting Machines, Clustering

Computer Vision Feature Detection, Matching, Tracking, Optical Flow, Visual Odometry

Data Engineering Apache Beam, Apache Spark, Tensorflow Extended (TFX), AWS Lambda Batch S3, Docker

Robotics ROS, Gazebo Simulator, RViz, URDF

Embedded Linux, RTOS, Microcontrollers, DSP, Fieldbus, Distributed Controls

Education

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) Experimental High Energy Physics

H. H. WILLS PHYSICS LABORATORY, UNIVERSITY OF BRISTOL

1998 - 2001

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) Applied Physics (1st Class)

bachetor of Science (b.Sc.) Applied Filysics (13t)

STAFFORDSHIRE UNIVERSITY

Stoke-on-Trent, U.K. 1995 - 1998

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) Graphic Design (2nd Class)

Leeds, U.K.

Bristol, U.K.

LEEDS BECKETT UNIVERSITY

1989 - 1991

Courses _____

AMRx: Autonomous Mobile Robots

Locomotion, Perception, Localization, SLAM, Intelligent Navigation

ETH Zurich / edX

June 2021

Robotics Software Engineering Nanodegree

Udacity
March 2021

 $\label{thm:continuous} \mbox{Autonomous robotic development with ROS and Gazebo Simulator.}$

DeepLearning.Al

Advanced computer vision, generative deep learning, custom layers and loss Functions, distributed training.

Feb. 2021 Michigan / Coursera

Applied Machine Learning in Python

Tensorflow: Advanced techniques

Machine Learning, numpy, pandas, Scikit-learn, Classification, Clustering, Crossvalidation, Hyperparameters.

Apr. 2018

Applied Plotting, Charting and Data Representation in Python

Data Vizualization, numpy, pandas, matplotlib

Michigan / Coursera Feb. 2018

Machine Learning

Stanford / Coursera

Logistic Regression, Artifical Neural Networks, Machine Learning.

Jan. 2018 EPFL / Coursera

Functional Programming in Scala

Functional Programming, Big Data, Apache Spark, Parallel Computation.

Dec. 2017

Certifications

01.2021 Tensorflow Developer Certificate,

08.2017 Oracle Certified Associate: Java SE8 Programmer,

Tensorflow.org Oracle

05.2011 Scrum Master,

Scrum Alliance